<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Inquisitorial ? Delusional ? Philosophical ?</title>
  
  <subtitle>Equally insignificant to the vastness</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://barmy.me/"/>
  <updated>2019-02-16T22:37:31.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://barmy.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Vaibhav Agrawal</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The One With A Prophetic Dream</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2018/05-13-The-One-With-A-Prophetic-Dream.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2018/05-13-The-One-With-A-Prophetic-Dream.html</id>
    <published>2018-05-12T22:21:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:37:31.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We blindly follow and do things to satisfy God in the hope that God will reward us, but we mostly forget that God only rewards those who are true to help other humans and follow the religion of Humanity.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>I rarely get scared in my dreams but when I did get scared today afternoon it was when I foresaw humanity in its most terrible state.</p><p>So here’s the synopsis of the most terrible state humanity can lower itself down to.</p><p>Most of billions population follow a religion, and religion is the root source of all our troubles.</p><p>We blindly follow and do things to satisfy God in the hope that God will reward us, but we mostly forget that God only rewards those who are true to help other humans and follow the religion of Humanity.</p><p>One such degraded religion that came in my dream was composed of people who kill other people after a possible nuclear war and eat their hunt’s flesh. In Hinduism, we have the concept called Kalyug which warn us of the same.</p><p>Most of the South part of the world was captured by these flesh-eating animals, and I was trying to run away from them, but one of their people captured me to convert me into their religion by blackmailing me to hunger death to eat my fellow brotherhood’s flesh.</p><p>I got converted then they captured the world leader of the other type of religion which was against it so that they can finally convert everybody to their faith.</p><p>My dream got broken till I can finish the rest state of humanity to which it can perish.</p><p><code>Its a warning call.</code></p><p>The dream feels so much prophetic that I shit my pants remembering it, I get few prophetic dreams once in a while.</p><p>All I can hope right now at this moment is to work and hope this mother earth will give us one last chance to prove ourselves that we care about our Mother on the Mother’s Day. :(</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;We blindly follow and do things to satisfy God in the hope that God will reward us, but we mostly forget that God only rewards those who are true to help other humans and follow the religion of Humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Cigarette Seller Who Has A Side Business Of Eggs</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2018/03-16-The-cigarette-seller-who-has-a-side-business-of-eggs.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2018/03-16-The-cigarette-seller-who-has-a-side-business-of-eggs.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-15T22:09:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:13:50.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While having my smoke, I noticed he was arranging eggs just side of his cigarette shop…</p><p>I noticed that there is a chicken shop just side of his shop.</p><p>His business was getting threatened by that side shop, so he started selling eggs as a side business.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>While coming from Vrindavan… We took a break so that I can have a cigarette. :|</p><p>Asked for a big one but the guy (who was just somewhere of age 10-15) had only small ones.</p><p>So in my ignorance, I asked its only for 10 INR right.</p><p>The seller said in anger its only of 6 INR babu Ji…</p><p>Seeing his anger, I bought 2 from him…</p><p>While having my smoke, I noticed he was arranging eggs just side of his cigarette shop…</p><p>The sight in itself is quite rare, so I saw it further.</p><p>I noticed that there is a chicken shop just side of his shop.</p><p>Immediately I realized the reason for it.</p><p>His business was getting threatened by that side shop, so he started selling eggs as a side business. See the intelligence behind his action.</p><p>Every war and business is won by intelligence like that of Krishna in Mahabharat rather than proudness like sometimes we humans become susceptible to.</p><p>I asked his name…</p><p>He said Chand babu. ( Babu is another intelligence by his chief executioner Mom. 📷;) 📷:P )</p><p>I said Chand babu tum life me bohut aage jaoge bas humesha apni dukan/business chalana. He he 📷:) 📷</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;While having my smoke, I noticed he was arranging eggs just side of his cigarette shop…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I noticed that there is a chicken shop just side of his shop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His business was getting threatened by that side shop, so he started selling eggs as a side business.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Lost And Found Case Of The Sanjeevani Booti</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2018/02-16-The-Lost-And-Found-Case-Of-The-Sanjeevani-Booti.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2018/02-16-The-Lost-And-Found-Case-Of-The-Sanjeevani-Booti.html</id>
    <published>2018-02-15T22:15:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:20:04.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While enquiring more about it, he got to know that the plant which he was selling with a different name is actually Sanjeevani Booti.</p><p>He had been selling it for the past 7 years, and since nobody used to believe him that its Sanjeevi Booti, he stopped telling the real name of this plant.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Real story</p><p>Those who follow Hinduism must already have heard of metaphysical importance behind folklore of Sanjeevani Booti.</p><p>Its a medicinal herb used by Ram Ji to save Lakshman Ji which was very bravely brought by Hanuman Ji (whole mountain).</p><p>While our reporter was going through the busy streets of Nehru Place, he found a guy selling a very curious plant.</p><p>The plant was dead and dry but when you dip it inside water for a few days all the dead leaves and roots regain their life without any exception.</p><p>You might be thinking this happens to every plant through photosynthesis, but there is a big difference when each leaf regains their life against new leaves being created by other kinds of similar plant.</p><p>While enquiring more about it, he got to know that the plant which he was selling with a different name is actually Sanjeevani Booti.</p><p><code>He had been selling it for the past 7 years, and since nobody used to believe him that it&#39;s Sanjeevi Booti, he stopped telling the real name of this plant.</code><br>It can be verified from google image search results that what he was saying is actually entirely accurate.</p><p>Like how its written in the folklore of Hinduism the plant has almost every imagined medical benefit to your body provided you eat its green leaves.</p><p>Our reporter took a photo of the guy selling Sanjeevani Boots inside Nehru Place of New Delhi.</p><p>Interested Audience can buy it at a meager rate of 20 INR/piece or 50 INR/ 3 pieces.</p><p>Our reporter then gave the Sanjeevani Booti to the guy who was being dead…. Magic happened, and he is alive again. 😛</p><p><code>Those who don’t look for magic will never find it.</code></p><p><img src="https://whyburnlater.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/img_20180214_141523.jpg?w=1640" alt="Alt"></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;While enquiring more about it, he got to know that the plant which he was selling with a different name is actually Sanjeevani Booti.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He had been selling it for the past 7 years, and since nobody used to believe him that its Sanjeevi Booti, he stopped telling the real name of this plant.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Startup Of Startup Winters</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2017/02-24-A-Startup-Of-Startup-Winters.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2017/02-24-A-Startup-Of-Startup-Winters.html</id>
    <published>2017-02-23T22:04:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:07:57.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adaptability, perseverance, hard work, customer satisfaction were the topics being discussed every day which have been left out in the glamour of exponential growth, momentum, and exposure during summers of 13-15.</p><p>News of Companies getting shut down and employees released was no news at all in this startup winter.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p><code>A blessing in disguise it is.</code></p><p>When life gives you lemons you make lemonades, however, there were lemons but no water to make lemonade. 😐</p><p>The most chaotic situation a startup can face is imminent changes to the Indian economy, demonetization, and lack of external funds, resources or support.</p><p>however creativity is only born in chaos, it is only sustained in lack of stability, it is only valued in the absence of security.</p><p>Something unique can only come out of this chaos, as life came into existence through numerous chaotic possibilities.</p><p>Adaptability, perseverance, hard work, customer satisfaction were the topics being discussed every day which have been left out in the glamour of exponential growth, momentum, and exposure during summers of 13-15.</p><p>News of Companies getting shut down and employees released was no news at all in this startup winter.</p><p><code>Even unicorns felt its heat or lack of heat.</code> 😛</p><p>And baby cockroaches were devoured and hunted by this winter even before they were able to grow.</p><p>Discussions on revenue rather than a 10x return based on user acquisition were what investors and startup pandits were looking for.</p><p>What it showed to young entrepreneurs was a lesson worth it,</p><p><code>That old saying of the customer is always right is in fact true.</code></p><p>That is treating your employees with respect and dignity is a must.</p><p>Treating people as people rather than machines is a must.</p><p>Excellence is something to thrive for rather than exposure and glamour.</p><p>That starting up is something more than a startup, something closer to running a business.</p><p>That early adopters of startup summers are as much flawed and imperfect as we are.</p><p>That an enterprise is for the people, by the people and its foundations are its building blocks.</p><p>That when life punches you hard on your face, you have to stay strong and pull your team up along with you.</p><p>That a leader is not someone who is invulnerable he/she can also be knocked off with one hard punch too….</p><p>But a good leader is someone who keeps walking or even crawling to motivate his/her followers to do the same and together become a support system for each other.</p><p>That support is by your team rather than an enormous amount of funds you raise.</p><p>That is sometimes waiting to think about what should be the next steps is more critical than plunging into the first idea or opportunity one can see. 🙂</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Adaptability, perseverance, hard work, customer satisfaction were the topics being discussed every day which have been left out in the glamour of exponential growth, momentum, and exposure during summers of 13-15.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;News of Companies getting shut down and employees released was no news at all in this startup winter.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Memory With A Hockey Team</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2017/01-18-A-Memory-With-A-Hockey-Team.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2017/01-18-A-Memory-With-A-Hockey-Team.html</id>
    <published>2017-01-17T21:57:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:03:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Metro train was quite empty opposed to general peak time crowd, and quite many of seats were empty, so I sat on an empty bench.</p><p>On one of the many metro stations in between a team of hockey players came in a group, men and women included with their hockey kits.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>So here it starts.</p><p>While I was living in Gurgaon and like any Delhi NCR resident, I take great pride in traveling in India’s one the best public commute system that is Delhi metro.</p><p>On one of those days, I was randomly traveling from a metro station to my destination (can’t remember which… too long since it has happened).</p><p>Metro train was quite empty opposed to general peak time crowd, and quite many of seats were empty, so I sat on an empty bench.</p><p>On one of the many metro stations in between a team of hockey players came in a group, men and women included with their hockey kits.</p><p>It was quite apparent they all were Haryanavi Jatts 🙂</p><p>One of the girls sat just beside me, she was quite conscious of her body language.</p><p>After some time train started to fill up until a point that not a single seat was empty.</p><p>A guy came and asked me to make some room between her and me so he can sit in between, he was quite older to both of us.</p><p>And all the men in the hockey team were standing near the gate (They didn’t sit even if there were empty seats, taking pride in standing) laughing and chatting in their own unique, hilarious way of Jatts. 🙂</p><p>I tried to warn the guy asking for a seat between to remain silent and just leave and stand somewhere else, he keeps on persisting to make space, digging his own hole to die.</p><p>I looked towards the leader of their team, and he signaled me to hold my ground and keep sitting.</p><p>He again egoistically and proudly asked me to make room for him (You know thoda adjust to chalta hai).</p><p>This time the leader spoke and signaling his hands towards his own thighs told the ignorant guy to sit on his lap. (Ae baawli pooch aaja idhar baith ja)</p><p>All the girls/women and men started laughing, and the guy had to leave all red in anger.</p><p>This is what you call haryanavi blood (like my mom has in hers).</p><p>They can quickly teach you lessons by breaking all your bones and spilling your blood using their hockey unless you learn your lessons only by words.</p><p>Remember to never mess with a haryanavi. I would definitely not. 😐</p><p>PS: Watching dangal with my flatmate sure bring unexpected result in the form of memory long forgotten.</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Metro train was quite empty opposed to general peak time crowd, and quite many of seats were empty, so I sat on an empty bench.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On one of the many metro stations in between a team of hockey players came in a group, men and women included with their hockey kits.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Decision Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/12-21-What-Decision-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/12-21-What-Decision-Is.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-20T21:49:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T21:57:24.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Decision is when you took a leap of faith.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p><code>Decision is when you took a leap of faith.</code></p><p><code>Decision is when you have decided someone’s fate.</code></p><p><code>All along the way….</code></p><p><code>All along the way….</code></p><p>PS: It’s winter, downtime… taking up to read a book, The devil and Miss Prym. Like always the first exciting book I happen to see or hear from any social media channel or friend.</p><p>PPS: Watch out for Rania Naim, quite a thoughtful writer I came across.</p><p>PPPS: My first and all-time favorite spoken poetry.</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/mdJ6aUB2K4g" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Click Here</a></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Decision is when you took a leap of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What A Monster Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/12-19-What-A-Monster-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/12-19-What-A-Monster-Is.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-18T21:43:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:55:19.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By doing this, all you are achieving is creating more hate inside me for you and this world.</p><p>My love couldnt die or decrease for you.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>A diary entry of a monster….</p><p>What are you doing to me?</p><p>Why are you doing this to me?</p><p>I don’t want anything more than what you promised and lured me with.</p><p>By doing this, all you are achieving is creating more hate inside me for you and this world.</p><p>My love couldn’t die or decrease for you.</p><p>Day by day I am being consumed by this hate becoming a monster in its wake.</p><p>And one day you shall say I was a monster all along the way.</p><p>I shall prove myself to be one that day.</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;By doing this, all you are achieving is creating more hate inside me for you and this world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My love couldnt die or decrease for you.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Memory With The Sun</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/12-16-A-Memory-With-The-Sun.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/12-16-A-Memory-With-The-Sun.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-15T21:39:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T22:34:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a random memory that comes on the surface once in a while about my childhood, where my mom who is always a significant source of teachings and motivation, taught me that /Idiom.</p><p>I couldnt understand the point and teaching behind that idiom back then and after few attempts and arguing I gave up on discussing it with my mom, being a thoughtless child to think about something else that may interest me.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Heya,</p><p>Before I start lemme build a small background about what I am gonna cover in this post.</p><p>So there is a popular saying in Hindi such as “चढ़ते सूरज को सब सलाम करते है !”</p><p>Which transform into English idiom: Worshippers of the rising sun.</p><p>Meaning</p><p>To be with the successful.</p><p>There is a random memory that comes on the surface once in a while about my childhood, where my mom who is always a significant source of teachings and motivation, taught me that मुहावरा/Idiom.</p><p>Me being a thoughtless child questioned and argued with her No.</p><p>डूबता सूरज को सब सलाम करते ह ै! – Worshipping the sun when its set.</p><p>I even gave a reason as to why it is true since our sun has given us all the light and life for that whole day, we should be grateful for it when it sets.</p><p>Ohh Almighty Sun, you have done your purpose today.</p><p>I couldn’t understand the point and teaching behind that idiom back then and after few attempts and arguing I gave up on discussing it with my mom, being a thoughtless child to think about something else that may interest me.</p><p>It is only when I have grown up and saw the real world on and about the first time I tasted a small success after school, I get to understand the deep meaning behind that phrase.</p><p>We humans never learn from our mistakes, we tag along to causes and people who are on rising like mad and crazy worshippers or भक्त and start thrashing the same cause and people when we see them going downwards or setting to prepare for a new rise next day.</p><p>Be its cricket team, dictators, politicians, actors or businessman.</p><p>The recent thing I can think of is that of Flipkart and Ola and the public thrashing they are enduring.</p><p>Let’s be grateful to that fact that Flipkart is the one and the sole company which can be attributed to preparing the Indian market to accept online payments, to build trust that what you order will be delivered at your doorsteps. It takes a small amount of effort to grow on something that has already been started. But a lot to go against the tides.</p><p>I am not a fan of the current way they are doing things and wasn’t for few things they did before.</p><p>But in the end we all are humans, and we make mistakes. And I hope we will learn from our mistakes someday and evolve together as a society to reach new heights, else extinction is inevitable.</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;There is a random memory that comes on the surface once in a while about my childhood, where my mom who is always a significant source of teachings and motivation, taught me that /Idiom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldnt understand the point and teaching behind that idiom back then and after few attempts and arguing I gave up on discussing it with my mom, being a thoughtless child to think about something else that may interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Destiny Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/04-02-What-Destiny-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/04-02-What-Destiny-Is.html</id>
    <published>2016-04-01T20:57:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T21:02:39.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Humans by their nature are social animals and like ants need the order to survive in this world order is our foremost need, ever wonder why all the laws and social stigma or institutions or leaders which have dealt such a damage to humanity yet people didnt resist the order at the time they should be led into a war against their own flesh and blood, i.e. another human.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>We all have always found ourselves in many or at least one incidence where we used the ideology of destiny or have seen our surrounding setting making a reference to it.</p><p>No??</p><p>Of course, we have it makes us feel that there is a purpose and we will get that no matter what. It makes us feel relevant to this world which is so vast and enormous both outwardly and inwardly. In many dimensions, we humans have tapped into and many we have yet to.</p><p>Now behold my amigos we shall question, and I am gonna take you on a hell of a ride if you are a total believer of destiny slowly then profoundly. You just have to bear the mental simulation.</p><p>Let’s start !!!!</p><p>Cause.</p><p>How is it created what its source is?</p><p>Affinity for an order that is resistance to change.<br>The easiest way to fall into the trap of making one belief in destiny is this one. Humans by their nature are social animals and like ants need the order to survive in this world order is our foremost need, ever wonder why all the laws and social stigma or institutions or leaders which have dealt such a damage to humanity yet people didn’t resist the order at the time they should be led into a war against their own flesh and blood, i.e. another human.</p><p>Belief in free will or independence and Marxist sociology will lead to the conclusion of a tilted balance towards randomness or chaos in our life or the whole meaning of life. If it unfolds how we act and think then you get the point too much to write. aha 😐</p><p>Need to fit in the world.<br>We have never understood the creator of this world or never even can that’s why he is creator also the fact that we align the creation with a creator which can be inherently assumed as a living entity. We understand things only based on what we see if there is a scientist who invents then there must be a creator who created this world?? Indeed such a pity for us.</p><p>As we can’t and made the false assumption, we are doomed to believe that if there is a creator then definitely he must have some scripted life for me. Even going by that he is a creator not a puppet master. He will have better things to create rather than tend to them.</p><p>We don’t understand this world, so we make a false assumption, and hence we finally got us into believing into destiny/fate/karma.</p><p>Hope.<br>Hope lead us to believe in the concept of destiny in many ways unimaginable.</p><p>If we have already got into the trap of the above two causes which in most of the cases we do. Then the task for hope is simple when reality hits, and we can’t clearly see our purpose we make hope our ally to battle on the side of destiny.</p><p>If not then by nature we are expectant for order in our lives, means like something should happen as we want otherwise we will retaliate or get devastated. Life will hit us again and again with its reality till the point we leave expectations side towards hope itself, broken and tired and what will hope say life will be good you are destined to be happy. (Haha sucker hope though) .</p><p>Too much for the cause. Don’t feel like extending this more you must be tired of reading also.</p><p>Conclusion on its way.</p><p>Think about some quotations on destiny get riled up.</p><p>Like this one destiny is the bridge we build to the one we love. One from my fav movie My sassy girl ❤ Do watch it sometime if you haven’t. Bold and confused</p><p>You have to show up to the place your destiny meets you follow patterns be true to yourself go deep courageously year after year.</p><p>You have to seize your destiny from the hands of forces if there is anything as such.</p><p>All in all</p><p>Destiny in two lines according to my introspection and conclusion way back.</p><p>Only those who have achieved the highest and purest self of themselves being in this world have the privilege to call out to this world I was destined to be here not before not after just at that moment of infinite resourcefulness that particular person has experienced.</p><p>Once we have reached your dreams can you say we were destined to be here not before? Till then work hard to achieve your goals.</p><p>I promised to take you all on a hell of a ride, but I failed its only part one of my views and conclusion of destiny in a very shallow philosophical manner.</p><p>The other part is too complicated and weird for one to understand.</p><p>Watch out for part two again when I feel the motivation to pull this topic again.</p><p>Sneak peek … karma, sufferings, how destiny is decided for a particular person, why some people don’t pay for their evil deeds and some always end up, and its relation with the formation of destiny.</p><p>PS: Ahah! Moment for me yesternight.</p><p>A flashback behind the conclusion I made about destiny hit me today. It was in a second year sitting inside the computer lab playing some stupid MMORPG game.</p><p>PPS: Sometimes I feel its a drag to ponder over philosophy alone, so much so less I know.</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Humans by their nature are social animals and like ants need the order to survive in this world order is our foremost need, ever wonder why all the laws and social stigma or institutions or leaders which have dealt such a damage to humanity yet people didnt resist the order at the time they should be led into a war against their own flesh and blood, i.e. another human.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The One With A Dad And Son</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/02-21-The-One-With-A-Dad-And-Son.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/02-21-The-One-With-A-Dad-And-Son.html</id>
    <published>2016-02-20T20:51:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:55:22.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Out of the blue, I heard a noisy disturbance of a scooter on having a look found a dad driving a scooter with his son standing on the space between the seat and handle, and rushing to another end of the long road in a zig-zag manner but the funny part is the boy and his smile On each cross of roads, dad was blowing horns as to announce the world get away worldly troubles my son is laughing.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Heya,</p><p>Night time</p><p>Sitting in the balcony, in my own thoughts of solitude yeah it’s scary sometimes to imagine how can someone spend so much time alone, 😐</p><p>Out of the blue, I heard a noisy disturbance of a scooter on having a look found a dad driving a scooter with his son standing on the space between the seat and handle, and rushing to another end of the long road in a zig-zag manner but the funny part is the boy and his smile</p><p>he was an average child with specs and thin body type and was laughing his ass out in the process.</p><p>On each cross of roads, dad was blowing horns as to announce the world get away worldly troubles my son is laughing.</p><p>I remember riding on my papa’s scooter when he used to do the same all around our locality and hating why did he always put me in that position, I wanted to ride one, being a free spirit… lol, stupid kid.</p><p>I even remember saying once in front of my cousin Arru didi in Bangalore.. jab main scooter chalayunga to papa ko aage khada karunga 😐</p><p>Then motorcycle came yet the same story. All I got was a good bicycle to tame. stupidity and Responsibility can’t go hands in hands 😦 🙂</p><p>From whence I was adolescence whenever I used to come to home after JEE dad persisted me to learn, I learned half-heartedly but did learn. Finally, after college with a brand new bike, I could make that dream come true.</p><p>And I am sure my dad will be the one to teach me how to drive a car someday now when we have one waiting to test my hands at home so that eventually I can do the same for my future generation.</p><p>Its silly to see cues in these little things but that makes me understand the meaning of life.</p><p>Creation of life, growth and maybe someday far destruction 😦</p><p>For me past is not something to frown upon it is the mirror to acceptance and change.</p><p>Forgetting past may spare one happiness, but it definitely will take away the chance of achieving content. Inner peace.</p><p>Thanking all ohh hail forces of nature and</p><p>Special thanks to you for making me realize, this simple yet essential truth 🙂</p><p>for now</p><p>bye</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Out of the blue, I heard a noisy disturbance of a scooter on having a look found a dad driving a scooter with his son standing on the space between the seat and handle, and rushing to another end of the long road in a zig-zag manner but the funny part is the boy and his smile On each cross of roads, dad was blowing horns as to announce the world get away worldly troubles my son is laughing.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Birth Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2016/01-23-What-Birth-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2016/01-23-What-Birth-Is.html</id>
    <published>2016-01-22T20:40:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:49:50.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ohh its a hypothetical particle which explains space is not empty and instead of a fluid or ocean of Higgs boson particles which provide matter its mass…</p><p>It has been known for the past few decades that our universe is made up of something weird called dark matter and dark energy..?</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Heya,</p><p>Its a far more difficult topic to write than any of previous I wrote, however, let’s give it a try.. it’s going to be a long shot but worth the shot</p><p>before understanding birth, we should understand death..!!</p><p>Something doesn’t seem right? Does death come after birth?</p><p>exactly till birth to death, we have observations but what about from death to birth.</p><p>It would be nice for me to read my first post of what death is? Before I start on birth.</p><p>I don’t know exactly where to start from so much to write concisely.</p><p>Ok, I was always a prominent skeptic about rebirth and reincarnations or any of the theory be it religious or scientific however now all my thought experiments are pointing towards them.</p><p>Let’s take that from religious as well as scientific POV and then maybe nature can instill some insights.</p><p><code>Last thing first..</code></p><h3 id="Nature"><a href="#Nature" class="headerlink" title="Nature"></a>Nature</h3><p>We all can sense there are three forces that define it, each and everyday events oscillate around these three.</p><p><code>Creation, Growth, and Destruction.</code></p><p>The same entity or object or person or anything we know can be oscillated or manipulated or constructed to these characteristics,<br>Like for example, thoughts are creative or supporting growth or destructive. Nuclear force can be used to create, sustain civilizations or destroy. Same goes for people.</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/destruction-form-of-creation.png" alt="Alt"></p><h3 id="OSCILLATIONS"><a href="#OSCILLATIONS" class="headerlink" title="OSCILLATIONS"></a>OSCILLATIONS</h3><p>Creation and growth evolve together while destruction work opposite to them 😉 its not a bad thing it is how it is. None is right none is wrong.</p><p>So that means after destruction creation can take place? 😐</p><p>Oscillations go to string theory…</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/stringtheory_shutterstock_24627319.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><h3 id="Science"><a href="#Science" class="headerlink" title="Science"></a>Science</h3><p><code>Now science comes into the picture.</code></p><p>There is a big buzz around Higgs boson or God particle and building of a large particle collider. Michio Kaku is the guy behind string theory.</p><p>According to which every force or every energy or every particle can be understood as if at the core of the musical strings are oscillating on different notes each note changing the nature to something else.. be it an electron, proton.. be it gravitational, electro-magnetism force.</p><p>A real genius he is.. celebrating his birthday tomorrow 🙂 waiting for detection of sparticles (super particles) to test his theory in the same CERN particle collider, hope he succeeds. 😐</p><p>However, what about god’s particle or Higgs boson…</p><p>Ohh it’s a hypothetical particle which explains space is not empty and instead of a fluid or ocean of Higgs boson particles which provide matter its mass…</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/cartoon-explains-higgs-boson-video-1da878a096.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p>The more difficult for a matter to pass through this ocean the more drag it feels, the more mass it gains… WoW, let me read my post what past is? again 🙂</p><p>It has been known for the past few decades that our universe is made up of something weird called dark matter and dark energy..? seriously? When I first found out, I said come on give it a better name. 😦</p><p>Well they can’t be detected directly, they don’t interact with matter, or light particles so can’t be observed yet we sense them as ghosts of our universe because they do have mass and consists about 96% of the universe. Did I say ghosts?</p><p>Moreover, there is some dark energy which is pushing everything away from each other hence we hear universe is expanding.. but what exactly can this dark energy be?</p><p>I believe its soul energy which is contrary to its name given we all must already have a preconception of something dark about this energy 😦 😦 maybe scary Ghosts. 😐</p><p>let me explain how I believe that.</p><h3 id="Religion"><a href="#Religion" class="headerlink" title="Religion"></a>Religion</h3><p><code>Religion came into the rescue...</code></p><p>Tell me what you know about the soul or maybe heard from our ancestors or TV etc.</p><p>Well they are inside us… however, where exactly we don’t know for sure</p><p>we don’t know where it comes from what is its nature, characteristics</p><p>well, they don’t interact with our body but drive our body…</p><p>they do have some mass.. again controversial by some experiments on glass fitted dying body… damn these crazy scientists 😐</p><p>now think about whatever I said about dark energy.. everything matches?</p><p>Going by the concept of moksha when a body attains it, the soul becomes eternal it doesn’t have to take rebirth into a body. According to this and Kalki Puran as kalyug goes by more and more soul are united with God before destruction.</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/a-twin.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p>That means dark energy if it is genuinely soul energy will increase over time.</p><p>Which is a doubt in the scientific community whether dark energy remains the same or increase with time.</p><p>If it remains the same universe will expand into nothingness and if it increases then.</p><p>one day one moment every possible atom or matter will explode into destruction.</p><p>Hmm thinking it by this way makes me feel we are doomed for destruction. I may be wrong everything I concluded is wishful and dreamy with little proof.</p><p>However, hey I am not here to entertain your every doubt on me or my theories.</p><p>Moreover, here is a bonus…</p><p>Realistic speaking there are instances in history where people can recall their past lives there are a whole lot of articles and documentary on youtube and net, the biggest one is Reincarnation of Anne Frank after around 30 years or something as I remember.</p><p>By Hindu mythology, the nature of one true God can’t be known or understood which I got to know is according to Hinduism reading some posts on quora .. dammit I came to this conclusion way before these gitas and sitas.</p><p>Anyways for all those feminists out there who says there are no women in the three Gods of creation, growth, and destruction… Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesh</p><p>I believe society has hidden a long forgotten truth in that. The majority are feminine out of these three Gods of nature or gatekeepers who are ordinary souls but evolved to such extent to be idolized as Gods.</p><p>It’s your job to figure which two out of three are if you are worthy to know as a feminine.</p><p>haha just gone through some not my jobs memes. 😛 🙂</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/not-my-job.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p>Another thought which I discovered recently is a bit related to the above concept. there is no such thing as karma or getting bad for evil deeds and good for good</p><p>u get what u desire in the last moments of your death before rebirth u get a choice every day every moment to change your far (rebirth) and near future (present life).</p><p>PS: I am not over analyzing things don’t want to put any constraint on the ideas as opposed to what society tries to, who r they to tell us how everything works here. We all must have heard about the famous monkey shower experiment. We don’t need anyone’s approval to think and do things we feel like to. On the downside, too much of that is terrible. Balance is what we should seek…</p><p>repeat with me .. I am an individual independent citizen of society who has every bit of right to question social reforms for our betterment.</p><p>Screw them…</p><p>repeat with me .. I love and care about society until unless it doesn’t try to change me.</p><p>Screw you guys I am going home 😛 and if nothing makes sense screw me too… Huh?</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/6a00d8341cb36153ef019aff422b8c970c-320wi.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p>PPS: Here is a video by Michio Kaku on consciousness how to define it and measure it</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/AAEB-5GOCJ4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">video</a></p><p>Watch out for physics girl and her website believed to be next Einstein by Harvard.</p><p>PPS: Life has retaken an exciting turn, working on an idea I believe is the next big thing, taking up to read the brave new world, just got my elements cube after 3 months of waiting for delivery. Its winters.. time to hibernate 😐</p><p>bye</p><p>for now 😐</p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/a8my7p6_700b_v1.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Ohh its a hypothetical particle which explains space is not empty and instead of a fluid or ocean of Higgs boson particles which provide matter its mass…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been known for the past few decades that our universe is made up of something weird called dark matter and dark energy..?&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Memory With A Chai Wala</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/09-21-A-Memory-With-A-Chai-Wala.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/09-21-A-Memory-With-A-Chai-Wala.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-20T20:34:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:38:29.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He said haan, took a chai although I rarely like to drink chai voluntarily Then a carwala and then a bikewala came for chai and cigarettes, waited for them to go.</p><p>Sipping my chai slowly, the reason?? haan abhi to yaha pe lagana shuru kiya hai to jyada log nahi jaante, agar jyada log nahi aate to dusre signal me chale jate hain. aap yahan ke to nahi lagte aapki hindi achhi hai..</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Ohh the Night and the long rides, some part of all of us loves that.. either reacted with great company or serenity of our own minds.</p><p>while one of those bike rides, I came across a chaiwala on sidelines of a highway.</p><p>when I lazily saw a guy standing by his bicycle with a big bottle of milton tea, the way his expectant eyes were seeing me made me stop and look what life has to offer.</p><p>when asked aapke paas chai hai?</p><p>he said haan, took a chai although I rarely like to drink chai voluntarily (burns ur tongue dammit)</p><p>Then a carwala and then a bikewala came for chai and cigarettes, waited for them to go.</p><p>sipping my chai slowly, the reason??</p><p>A sense of innocence and not belonging to the city.</p><p>After the others are gone, silence is broken.</p><p>Aap roj aate ho yahan raat me?</p><p>haan</p><p>roj raat me 11-12 baje?</p><p>haan abhi to yaha pe lagana shuru kiya hai to jyada log nahi jaante, agar jyada log nahi aate to dusre signal me chale jate hain.</p><p>aap yahan ke to nahi lagte aapki hindi achhi hai..</p><p>He agreed and said in dis encouraging voice UP.</p><p>sahi main bhi UP ka hun, aisa kuch nhi hai 🙂</p><p>aapki family wahi pe?</p><p>haan hum abhi aaye hai yahan 2-3 mahine hue hai.</p><p>Gosh smile is so contagious. 🙂</p><p>after the payment of overpriced “8 rupees” chai, I started off on my bike but happened to forget my key to the lock of the seat, when searching for it he told its there only.</p><p>A thanks bhaiya and I am off.</p><p>On my way, I imagined how he must have come from somewhere to establish him in this city.</p><p>Maybe by his advisories, he got to know the need of chai sutta chronicle in the city who does sleep. 🙂</p><p>Don’t know about him but I have got my chai sutta chronicle tonight. 😐</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;He said haan, took a chai although I rarely like to drink chai voluntarily Then a carwala and then a bikewala came for chai and cigarettes, waited for them to go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sipping my chai slowly, the reason?? haan abhi to yaha pe lagana shuru kiya hai to jyada log nahi jaante, agar jyada log nahi aate to dusre signal me chale jate hain. aap yahan ke to nahi lagte aapki hindi achhi hai..&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Love Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/03-26-What-Love-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/03-26-What-Love-Is.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-25T20:28:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:34:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its the last day for your relationship with any particular person You become a person with whom the concerned person will always have something to take advantage of You become a person, being with whom always suits them You become that person according to the needs of the concerned person like money, emotional stability, sex anything and then People always say mothers love is the purest form of love</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p><strong>A Harsh truth –</strong><br><code>“What suits you hurts you.”</code></p><p><code>People come to your life when it suits them.</code></p><p><code>They love you when it suits them.</code></p><p><code>They hurt you when it suits them.</code></p><p><code>They leave you when it suits them.</code></p><p>If you want to prevent yourself from being hurt then<br>either you accept the fact and live each day of your life as if<br>its the last day for your relationship with any particular person<br>and be on constant watch that he/she may hurt you and leave you<br>which is a sad choice of course</p><p>or you take another sad choice where<br>you become a person with whom the concerned person will always have something to take advantage of<br>you become a person, being with whom always suits them<br>and you become that person according to the needs of the concerned person like money, emotional stability, sex anything and then</p><p>you lose ur identity</p><p>People always say mothers love is the purest form of love<br>I agree with it a bit .. not wholly<br>The purest form of love is that of mother and child<br>because the child is the only true being, the only innocent human being who is unaltered by this harsh reality of life</p><p>and a child love for you is the best gift you can get</p><p>We have numerous examples in history where two children fall in love, and then they try to fight the world for their love even when they are separated for years, e.g., Romeo Juliet, Heer Ranjha, Devdas 😉<br>Why so? Because that is innocent love…</p><p>love when you don’t even know the meaning of what suits you is</p><p>PS: The first blog entry post I wrote around a year and a half ago 🙂</p><p>PPS: Just being a dreamer and delusional as I always am 😐</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Its the last day for your relationship with any particular person You become a person with whom the concerned person will always have something to take advantage of You become a person, being with whom always suits them You become that person according to the needs of the concerned person like money, emotional stability, sex anything and then People always say mothers love is the purest form of love&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="love" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/love/"/>
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Hope Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/03-23-What-Hope-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/03-23-What-Hope-Is.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-22T20:20:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:27:23.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hope is something when we believe some event has a probability of happening in near or distant future and acknowledging side by side that It may not happen at all, When reality rears its ugly head, and we accept that the thing we were hoping and expecting didnt happen it leads to big disappointment, and…</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>One of the best lessons I learned about hope from my encounter with a beautiful person is about Hope.</p><p>Hope is a very tricky thing we all humans possess.</p><p>Let’s start with understanding when and why we hope.</p><p>we all are unsatisfied with something or other at every point of our life.</p><p>The greater the fear and confusion the greater we hope.</p><p>however, hope leads to expectations which lead to disappointment right?</p><p>we will see if the above statement is correct</p><p>hope is something when we believe some event has a probability of happening in near or distant future and acknowledging side by side that It may not happen at all,</p><p>that there is very little chance, the thing we are hoping can happen</p><p>while the expectation is defined as believing that even if there is a slight chance, it will happen.</p><p>and when reality rears its ugly head, and we accept that the thing we were hoping and expecting didn’t happen it leads to big disappointment, and…</p><p>we lose our faith on hope.</p><p>So the only way to retain our faith on hope is to hope but not expecting anything at all.</p><p>however simple the above statement seems it is the most difficult thing to practice,</p><p>to keep away expectations from hope is to keep away two people with one soul 😉</p><p>It’s painful, and it’s awful.</p><p>so the next time u hope something starts practicing this question.</p><p>What I am expecting is it feasible, is it actually probable and possible.</p><p><code>To keep the heart unwrinkled, to be hopeful, kindly, cheerful, and reverent: that is the triumph over old age.</code></p><p><code>Thomas Aldrich</code></p><p><img src="https://immosmeaningoflife.files.wordpress.com/2015/03/hope-for-the-best.png" alt="Alt"></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Hope is something when we believe some event has a probability of happening in near or distant future and acknowledging side by side that It may not happen at all, When reality rears its ugly head, and we accept that the thing we were hoping and expecting didnt happen it leads to big disappointment, and…&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Past Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/03-19-What-Past-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/03-19-What-Past-Is.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-18T20:15:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:50:33.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In that lecture, our professor was teaching us how a ball experience greater force while traveling in a viscous fluid.</p><p>The higher the viscosity of fluid its traveling in, the higher the drag, the rougher the surface of the ball, the more drag it experiences.</p><p>Suppose you are the ball traveling in the flow of life and the fluid is your experience in it.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>I was a chemical engineer once, and the only worthwhile lesson I learned from one of my boring lectures was on past</p><p>In that lecture, our professor was teaching us how a ball experience greater force while traveling in a viscous fluid.</p><p>with some formulas of course 😉</p><p>which is called drag.</p><p>The higher the viscosity of fluid it’s traveling in, the higher the drag, the rougher the surface of the ball, the more drag it experiences.</p><p>coming back to what past is?</p><p>suppose you are the ball traveling in the flow of life and the fluid is your experience in it.</p><p>the more difficult ur life is the more drag u face</p><p>sometimes it drags u behind, sometimes it stops you</p><p>sometimes it let u pass without any resistance</p><p>hence proved</p><p>Past is a Drag</p><p>however, does that mean we should avoid it?</p><p>never</p><p>the more u try to resist ur past the more drag u will experience like a rough ball faces</p><p>Only when u have come to a free-flowing life, u will miss the struggle u faced and came out as a winner</p><p>Only when u have learned how to avoid the drag by being a smooth ball</p><p>u will get the strength to face another drag of the universally resented past.</p><p>PS: Watching friends and listening to some touching songs sure bring unexpected results from my subconscious mind taking the form of a memory long forgotten. 😐</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;In that lecture, our professor was teaching us how a ball experience greater force while traveling in a viscous fluid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The higher the viscosity of fluid its traveling in, the higher the drag, the rougher the surface of the ball, the more drag it experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you are the ball traveling in the flow of life and the fluid is your experience in it.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Does A Hero Truly Need?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/02-14-What-Does-A-Hero-Truly-Need.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/02-14-What-Does-A-Hero-Truly-Need.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-13T20:02:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T20:14:04.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The question arises what does that special girl have to have to be the main character in our heros life and our readers story?</p><p>Date a girl who laughs, cries and laugh again for no sensible reason known Date a girl with whom you dont need to break awkward silence because it isnt awkward Date a girl who is imaginative, so that u feel this world is too real for its own sake Date a girl who calls you 2 in the morning if she is confused or if she is too drunk to be confused</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>We all have a story attached to our life, or the fact our whole life is a story</p><p>Either lost in oblivion or not.</p><p>Like in every great story there is Love, sadness, adventure, confusion, mystery, and fear.</p><p>So there has to be a hero in our story too.</p><p>And what does a hero need to make his story complete?</p><p>A Women he adores</p><p>So the question arises <code>what does that special girl have to have to be the main character in our hero’s life and our reader&#39;s story?</code></p><p><code>Nothing</code></p><p><code>There is no secret ingredient.</code> To make someone special, you just have to believe she is special.</p><p>For all of us mere mortals bound to this reality, I am putting my two cents. 😉</p><ul><li>Date a girl who laughs, cries and laugh again for no sensible reason known</li><li>Date a girl who seems to be always high on life</li><li>Date a girl who stands up for something she feels like to</li><li>Date a girl who contradicts you just for the sake of fun</li><li>Date a girl with whom you can talk without the constraint of time</li><li>Date a girl with whom you don’t need to break awkward silence because it isn’t awkward</li><li>Date a girl who is commanding yet cute</li><li>Date a girl who is imaginative, so that u feel this world is too real for its own sake</li><li>Date a girl who is imperfect, weird, mad, crazy, stupid yet perfect for u</li><li>Date a girl who calls you 2 in the morning if she is confused or if she is too drunk to be confused</li><li>Date a girl you call with no reason whatsoever coz her voice is bliss to u</li><li>Date a girl who tells her boring daily errands to you because she has to</li><li>Date a girl who gives advice because she is concerned for u</li><li>Date a girl with whom you couldn’t break eye contact even if she is sitting far away from u</li><li>Date a girl who likes to do boy’s kinds of stuff because she doesn’t want to be left out</li><li>Date a girl who is your friend, enemy, mentor, motivation</li><li>Date a girl who despite being logical to her core, always follow her heart because it feels like to</li><li>Date a girl who is geeky with glasses yet when she sees u, you feel intense desire to be with</li><li>Date a girl who doesn’t get dolled up in makeup when she is with you because she is beautiful to you anyways</li><li>Date a girl who shuns you for something you did, but you both come in terms again anyway</li><li>Date a girl who laughs like a hippo on your dumbest jokes</li><li>Date a girl who loves a friendly banter yet apologize if you act you are mad</li><li>Date a girl who make numerous reasons for why you are right for her but none for why you aren’t</li><li><p>Date a girl who is conscious of you, but within no time she is the craziest person alive<br>and of course ……</p></li><li><p>Date a girl you find beautiful, you are hysterical with</p></li></ul><p><img src="https://i.pinimg.com/originals/c8/ff/9c/c8ff9c1f88388fffa7bb40e52c2a20f6.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/840NbiFF1zM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Love Song</a></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The question arises what does that special girl have to have to be the main character in our heros life and our readers story?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Date a girl who laughs, cries and laugh again for no sensible reason known Date a girl with whom you dont need to break awkward silence because it isnt awkward Date a girl who is imaginative, so that u feel this world is too real for its own sake Date a girl who calls you 2 in the morning if she is confused or if she is too drunk to be confused&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="love" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/love/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Memory With The 3 Musketeers</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/01-26-A-Memory-With-The-3-Musketeers.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/01-26-A-Memory-With-The-3-Musketeers.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-25T19:46:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T19:52:20.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A child beggar who was a boy came to me asking for money, I hesitated then fumbled my wallet to find some change money, found 3 rupees gave it to him in a matter of fact manner, and he went.</p><p>After around 10 sec saw two more child beggar this time a boy and a girl approaching me from the direction the previous one went.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>I was waiting outside a metro station before I board a metro to go hang out with my buddies in Noida.</p><p>A child beggar who was a boy came to me asking for money, I hesitated then fumbled my wallet to find some change money, found 3 rupees gave it to him in a matter of fact manner, and he went.</p><p>after around 10 sec saw two more child beggar this time a boy and a girl approaching me from the direction the previous one went.</p><p>The new boy asked me to give money, I gestured don’t have more change to offer and don’t want to give too, but he said</p><p>something like <code>aapne use 3 rupaiya diya humein kyun nahi, aur kuch bhi nahi?</code></p><p>I understood I couldn’t reason out of it now, started searching my wallet again while noticing the girl beside the other boy was watching me earnestly with her hand stretched and a note with few coins on it.</p><p>This time found a five rupees coin, gave it to the girl and said <code>aap donon share kar loge</code> with a gesture towards the boy and the money in her hand.</p><p>She instantly agreed on haan and asked me <code>main kitne dun ise?</code></p><p>I said in a gentle way <code>jo aapko achha lage.</code></p><p>She shared 2 rupees with him happily.</p><p>Then I observed them run and go towards the first boy I gave the 3 rupees to, and the other boy put the arms on the shoulder of the first boy, while the girl was watching them and moving with them side by side.</p><p>The way they were half jumping, half running, laughing .. it was infectious, which gave me a smile too.</p><p>It was a good feeling.</p><p>After some time few autos came in bulk, and many child beggars started running towards them, like a flock of chirping birds who have found their source of grain,</p><p>and the three children remained together this whole time both the boys laughing and going side by side arms on shoulders and the girl following them infected and curious by the conversation or joke they were cracking.</p><p>Breath taken by their friendship, affection, and innocence a thought crossed my mind……</p><p><code>THE THREE MUSKETEERS</code></p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;A child beggar who was a boy came to me asking for money, I hesitated then fumbled my wallet to find some change money, found 3 rupees gave it to him in a matter of fact manner, and he went.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After around 10 sec saw two more child beggar this time a boy and a girl approaching me from the direction the previous one went.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Life, Money And Friends Are?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/01-11-What-Life-Money-And-Friends-Are.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/01-11-What-Life-Money-And-Friends-Are.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-10T19:21:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T19:44:32.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Life me aisa kaam karna chahiye ki puri duniya tumhe jaane aur sadiyon tak yaad rakhe.</p><p>Tumne kuch aisa nahi kiya to bhi tumhe tumhari family aur bachhe kuch time tak yaad rakhenge after you die.</p><p>Sadiyan bhi kabhi khatam ho jayegi, time is relative my friend kam time ke liye kam log yaad rakhe, ya zyada time ke liye zyada log yaad rakhe.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>Excerpts of a conversation with one of my office mate while having a break.</p><h3 id="Life"><a href="#Life" class="headerlink" title="Life"></a>Life</h3><p><code>Life me aisa kaam karna chahiye ki puri duniya tumhe jaane aur sadiyon tak yaad rakhe.</code></p><p><code>Usse kya hoga?</code></p><p>Tumne kuch aisa nahi kiya to bhi tumhe tumhari family aur bachhe kuch time tak yaad rakhenge after you die.</p><p>Sadiyan bhi kabhi khatam ho jayegi, time is relative my friend kam time ke liye kam log yaad rakhe, ya zyada time ke liye zyada log yaad rakhe.</p><p>Outcome same hoga aek din, your name will be lost in the dust of history, Nobody can escape this cycle of time.</p><p>So why worry just do what you like to do and If it is written that many people will remember you for sadiyon tak, to badhiya hai nahi to koi tension nahi lene ka.</p><h3 id="Money"><a href="#Money" class="headerlink" title="Money"></a>Money</h3><p><code>Life me itna paisa hona chahiye ki jo tumne socha jab socha tab kar sako. If I want to go to the US today, I can go to.</code></p><p><code>Usse kya hoga?</code></p><p>Marna sabko hai aek na aek din ji ke marne ke liye paise nahi chahiye</p><p>Everyone live and die in this world from a cell to the extinct dinosaurs</p><p>The more complicated you let your mind and need become the more complex you make your life.</p><p>Take the example of a sloth, kya vo is baat se pareshan hai ki uski life kahan ja rhi hai?</p><p>He/She will die, you will die too.</p><p>outcome same hoga aek din.</p><p>So why worry just do what you would like to do in place of doing what you want to do, or you think you need to do.</p><h3 id="Friend"><a href="#Friend" class="headerlink" title="Friend"></a>Friend</h3><p><code>Life me sabse achhe dost kaun hote hai, school ke? College ke? Ya uske baad ke?</code></p><p><code>Abhi ke dost</code></p><p>sabse acche hote hain, live life in the present and take everyone as your friend.</p><p>Don’t get perturbed by the bereavement of your lost friends or the issues with the current ones and don’t get anxious as of will we make good friends. Have the courage to take things as they are and always ask this question when in doubt,</p><p><code>What is the next step?</code></p><p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71GOXTEEv%2BL._SX425_.jpg" alt="Alt"></p><p>PS: Phew some real shitty conversation out of nowhere, office work affected us I guess lol 😐</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Life me aisa kaam karna chahiye ki puri duniya tumhe jaane aur sadiyon tak yaad rakhe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tumne kuch aisa nahi kiya to bhi tumhe tumhari family aur bachhe kuch time tak yaad rakhenge after you die.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sadiyan bhi kabhi khatam ho jayegi, time is relative my friend kam time ke liye kam log yaad rakhe, ya zyada time ke liye zyada log yaad rakhe.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Memory With A Child Labour</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2015/01-01-A-Memory-With-A-Child-Labour.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2015/01-01-A-Memory-With-A-Child-Labour.html</id>
    <published>2014-12-31T19:15:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-02-16T19:19:09.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The tip money we give while we visit a restaurant has become a custom rather than the act of gratuity.</p><p>We should ask ourselves this question first how many time we feel obliged to give a tip when we go to a cheap restaurant or dhaba than I went there once because the of unavailability of food at late hours of the night , liked the food especially the daal fry, made a habit of eating there whenever I feel like to.</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>The tip money we give while we visit a restaurant has become a custom rather than the act of gratuity.</p><p>Because of which we tend to follow it only where we are conscious of our behavior,</p><p>like in a good restaurant where we are more afraid of being judged by the people surrounding us.</p><p>We should ask ourselves this question first how many time we feel obliged to give a tip when we go to a cheap restaurant or dhaba than</p><p>in the case when we go to a costly one who already takes a large amount of service tax.</p><p>So here is an incident I recently encountered which may make us question our motives of giving the tip money.</p><p>I like good and tasty food who doesn’t.</p><p>So there is a dhaba near my society which falls on the Gurgaon-Sohna highway, where truck drivers and other commuters eat en-route to their destination.</p><p>I went there once because the of unavailability of food at late hours of the night (its a 24/7 dhaba), liked the food especially the daal fry, made a habit of eating there whenever I feel like to.</p><p>Like my habit used to give the tip money of 10% to the waiter there too nothing abnormal here.</p><p>I started visiting it much so I became familiar with the waiters,</p><p>sometimes we exchange a word or few relating to my job timing and their home,</p><p>a joke here and there.</p><p>But this one day when I went there at around 2 is while my way back from office, I saw a new waiter who was child labor.</p><p>In contrast to other waiters, I have to say he surely was a very enthusiastic one considering the fact it is so cold here in winters that too in the hardest part of the night.</p><p>I liked the way he kept asking me, again and again, is something needed.</p><p>although trust me it is very irritating for me when somebody asks me .. Do I need anything. (Holy mother of God I will ask u by myself if I need anything .. lol :P)</p><p>I just stood up and took the salt from the neighboring table like I do many times…</p><p>It is a quicker way in place of asking a waiter to bide me his service.</p><p>He noticed it, and there was a sad expression.</p><p>So while billing, I gave him a double to the general tip of 10 rupees.</p><p>Now bear with me amigos what happened next hold a special place in my mind.</p><p>There was an expression of surprise and then ecstasy when I gave him 20 rupees as the tip,</p><p>and the way he took the note to his head in a religious way fitted everything perfectly.</p><p>Life sure is good, and people sure are fantastic. Religion eh interesting 🙂</p><p>haven’t seen him after that maybe should try different timings 😐</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The tip money we give while we visit a restaurant has become a custom rather than the act of gratuity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should ask ourselves this question first how many time we feel obliged to give a tip when we go to a cheap restaurant or dhaba than I went there once because the of unavailability of food at late hours of the night , liked the food especially the daal fry, made a habit of eating there whenever I feel like to.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="memory" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/memory/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Death Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2014/12-12-What-Death-Is.html"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2014/12-12-What-Death-Is.html</id>
    <published>2014-12-11T21:24:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-28T10:51:29.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the person didn’t even exist for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest NOTHINGNESS however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that<br><a id="more"></a><br>I recently encountered death of my grandfather and my maternal grandfather within a year.</p><p>It was a scary event , the way people take death as a tragedy is more <strong>infectious</strong> than it actually being a tragedy, it is a tragedy for someone with whom the concerned person is close. There always is a shower of unpredictable <strong>tears</strong> , all we can do is lend a consoling ear to people close to him/her .</p><p>However, is death something to be treated in <strong>hushed voices</strong>, we all are afraid to die, and the encounter with it makes us more afraid then we previously were.</p><p>I saw the terror and sense of <strong>seriousness</strong> around it felt like the air has become cold, like nothing good is going to happen in this world, hope is lost … it’s chilling to the core of bone</p><p>However, what exactly is death.</p><ul><li>Is it the seizure of all <strong>biological activities</strong>,</li><li>Is it the seizure of <strong>one’s consciousness,</strong></li><li>Is the start of a <strong>new journey</strong>.</li></ul><p>All the above explanations have their <strong>anomalies</strong>, seeing death as any of the above possible explanation would only give us pain and make us more confused.</p><p>How do we <strong>define consciousness?</strong></p><p>I am aware of who and what I am but then what about people who have lost consciousness and are in a coma and what about a single cell in our body who have a set of task to perform.</p><p>Is consciousness a <strong>by-product</strong> of the <strong>connections</strong> that are made by different <strong>neurons in the brain</strong>?</p><p>If I assume that a set of unconscious cell cant creates something that is conscious, then it means <strong>consciousness is external</strong> to the body which would lead to <strong>soul theory.</strong></p><p>If I assume that even a <strong>single cell</strong> could have <strong>consciousness</strong> then what is the way to <strong>define its consciousness.</strong></p><p>That would mean the way I am aware of myself could be different the way it is aware of itself.</p><p>I hope there is a new adventure after a person die because I don’t want to disappear into nothingness.</p><p>Another thing which crossed my mind is the <strong>life cycle</strong> of a person who dies. The <strong>TIME</strong> for which he lived</p><p>Since <strong>time is relative</strong> for different point for space in the <strong>universe</strong>. Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the <strong>person didn’t even exist</strong> for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest <strong>NOTHINGNESS</strong></p><p>However, for a <strong>supreme power</strong> which would be God everything and everyone must exist. Which would lead to the conclusion that for God the time scale goes so fast that everything would exist means no Gravity <strong>he must be unperturbed by Gravity.</strong> He must lie outside the boundary of the universe where is nothingness concerning space.</p><p>however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that</p><blockquote><p><em>“I am part and parcel of God and is equal to god in quality.”</em></p></blockquote><p>Let’s also associate the concept of <strong>heaven, hell and Brahma</strong>. Its written in Hindu mythology that <strong>a day for Brahma</strong> is equal to the <strong>life cycle of the earth</strong> and after that, he <strong>destroys</strong> everything and once again is <strong>created.</strong></p><p><strong>Brahma</strong> can have a <strong>time scale</strong> which may be <strong>relatively slow</strong>.</p><p>Could the <strong>destruction</strong> and <strong>rebirth</strong> be compared to the <strong>big bang</strong>, because a point from where big bang started also has a <strong>slow time scale</strong> and is a <strong>limit to singularity</strong> or <strong>infinite gravity</strong>?</p><p>PS: Life has retaken an exciting turn, reading Mein Kamph and Freud’s Interpretation of dreams, skating whenever I get the time to (it’s too cold), watched Interstellar.. awesome movie 🙂</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the person didn’t even exist for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest NOTHINGNESS however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
      <category term="physics" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/physics/"/>
    
      <category term="religion" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/religion/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
