<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Inquisitional ? Delusional ? Philosophical ?</title>
  
  <subtitle>Equally insignificant to the vastness</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://barmy.me/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-26T12:11:24.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://barmy.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Vaibhav Agrawal</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Death Is?</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/2014/12-12-What-Death-Is.htm"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/2014/12-12-What-Death-Is.htm</id>
    <published>2014-12-11T21:24:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-26T12:11:24.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the person didn’t even exist for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest NOTHINGNESS however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that<br><a id="more"></a><br>I recently encountered death of my grandfather and my maternal grandfather within a year.</p><p>It was a scary event , the way people take death as a tragedy is more <strong>infectious</strong> than it actually being a tragedy, it is a tragedy for someone with whom the concerned person is close. There always is a shower of unpredictable <strong>tears</strong> , all we can do is lend a consoling ear to people close to him/her .</p><p>However, is death something to be treated in <strong>hushed voices</strong>, we all are afraid to die, and the encounter with it makes us more afraid then we previously were.</p><p>I saw the terror and sense of <strong>seriousness</strong> around it felt like the air has become cold, like nothing good is going to happen in this world, hope is lost … it’s chilling to the core of bone</p><p>However, what exactly is death.</p><ul><li>Is it the seizure of all <strong>biological activities</strong>,</li><li>Is it the seizure of <strong>one’s consciousness,</strong></li><li>Is the start of a <strong>new journey</strong>.</li></ul><p>All the above explanations have their <strong>anomalies</strong>, seeing death as any of the above possible explanation would only give us pain and make us more confused.</p><p>How do we <strong>define consciousness?</strong></p><p>I am aware of who and what I am but then what about people who have lost consciousness and are in a coma and what about a single cell in our body who have a set of task to perform.</p><p>Is consciousness a <strong>by-product</strong> of the <strong>connections</strong> that are made by different <strong>neurons in the brain</strong>?</p><p>If I assume that a set of unconscious cell cant creates something that is conscious, then it means <strong>consciousness is external</strong> to the body which would lead to <strong>soul theory.</strong></p><p>If I assume that even a <strong>single cell</strong> could have <strong>consciousness</strong> then what is the way to <strong>define its consciousness.</strong></p><p>That would mean the way I am aware of myself could be different the way it is aware of itself.</p><p>I hope there is a new adventure after a person die because I don’t want to disappear into nothingness.</p><p>Another thing which crossed my mind is the <strong>life cycle</strong> of a person who dies. The <strong>TIME</strong> for which he lived</p><p>Since <strong>time is relative</strong> for different point for space in the <strong>universe</strong>. Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the <strong>person didn’t even exist</strong> for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest <strong>NOTHINGNESS</strong></p><p>However, for a <strong>supreme power</strong> which would be God everything and everyone must exist. Which would lead to the conclusion that for God the time scale goes so fast that everything would exist means no Gravity <strong>he must be unperturbed by Gravity.</strong> He must lie outside the boundary of the universe where is nothingness concerning space.</p><p>however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that</p><blockquote><p><em>“I am part and parcel of God and is equal to god in quality.”</em></p></blockquote><p>Let’s also associate the concept of <strong>heaven, hell and Brahma</strong>. Its written in Hindu mythology that <strong>a day for Brahma</strong> is equal to the <strong>life cycle of the earth</strong> and after that, he <strong>destroys</strong> everything and once again is <strong>created.</strong></p><p><strong>Brahma</strong> can have a <strong>time scale</strong> which may be <strong>relatively slow</strong>.</p><p>Could the <strong>destruction</strong> and <strong>rebirth</strong> be compared to the <strong>big bang</strong>, because a point from where big bang started also has a <strong>slow time scale</strong> and is a <strong>limit to singularity</strong> or <strong>infinite gravity</strong>?</p><p>PS: Life has retaken an exciting turn, reading Mein Kamph and Freud’s Interpretation of dreams, skating whenever I get the time to (it’s too cold), watched Interstellar.. awesome movie 🙂</p><blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Different people live for a different period and the place where time is static (the place of infinite gravity singularity) means the person didn’t even exist for that point nothing exists except the infinite state of rest NOTHINGNESS however, for a person who lives in a time scale like that of this earth, for example, everything and everyone exists too in a time scale then it can be said indeed that&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="philosophy" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/philosophy/"/>
    
      <category term="physics" scheme="http://barmy.me/tags/physics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://barmy.me/1990/09-23-hello-world.htm"/>
    <id>http://barmy.me/1990/09-23-hello-world.htm</id>
    <published>1990-09-22T22:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-26T09:33:08.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Am born and said hello to the world of possibilities and experiences!<br><a id="more"></a><br>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">"My New Post"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Am born and said hello to the world of possibilities and experiences!&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
